<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-08T13:25:28-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jon Saad-Falcon</title><author><name>Jon Saad-Falcon</name><email>jonsaadfalcon@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">EnergyVis: Interactively Tracking and Exploring Energy Consumption for ML Models</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/papers/energy-vis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EnergyVis: Interactively Tracking and Exploring Energy Consumption for ML Models" /><published>2021-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/papers/energyvis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/papers/energy-vis">&lt;p&gt;The advent of larger machine learning (ML) models have improved state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance in various modeling tasks, ranging from computer vision to natural language. As ML models continue increasing in size, so does their respective energy consumption and computational requirements. However, the methods for tracking, reporting, and comparing energy consumption remain limited. We presentEnergyVis, an interactive energy consumption tracker for ML models. Consisting of multiple coordinated views, EnergyVis enables researchers to interactively track, visualize and compare model energy consumption across key energy consumption and carbon footprint metrics (kWh and CO2), helping users explore alternative deployment locations and hardware that may reduce carbon footprints. EnergyVis aims to raise awareness concerning computational sustainability by interactively highlighting excessive energy usage during model training; and by providing alternative training options to reduce energy usage.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Omar Shaikh</name></author><summary type="html">The advent of larger machine learning (ML) models have improved state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance in various modeling tasks, ranging from computer vision to natural language. As ML models continue increasing in size, so does their respective energy consumption and computational requirements. However, the methods for tracking, reporting, and comparing energy consumption remain limited. We presentEnergyVis, an interactive energy consumption tracker for ML models. Consisting of multiple coordinated views, EnergyVis enables researchers to interactively track, visualize and compare model energy consumption across key energy consumption and carbon footprint metrics (kWh and CO2), helping users explore alternative deployment locations and hardware that may reduce carbon footprints. EnergyVis aims to raise awareness concerning computational sustainability by interactively highlighting excessive energy usage during model training; and by providing alternative training options to reduce energy usage.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/papers/21-energyvis-map.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/papers/21-energyvis-map.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Examining the Ordering of Rhetorical Strategies in Persuasive Requests</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/papers/persuasive-orderings" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Examining the Ordering of Rhetorical Strategies in Persuasive Requests" /><published>2020-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/papers/persuasive-orderings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/papers/persuasive-orderings">&lt;p&gt;Interpreting how persuasive language influences audiences has implications across many domains like advertising, argumentation, and propaganda. Persuasion relies on more than a message’s content. Arranging the order of the message itself (i.e., ordering specific rhetorical strategies) also plays an important role. To examine how strategy orderings contribute to persuasiveness, we first utilize a Variational Autoencoder model to disentangle content and rhetorical strategies in textual requests from a large-scale loan request corpus. We then visualize interplay between content and strategy through an attentional LSTM that predicts the success of textual requests. We find that specific (orderings of) strategies interact uniquely with a request’s content to impact success rate, and thus the persuasiveness of a request.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Omar Shaikh</name></author><summary type="html">Interpreting how persuasive language influences audiences has implications across many domains like advertising, argumentation, and propaganda. Persuasion relies on more than a message’s content. Arranging the order of the message itself (i.e., ordering specific rhetorical strategies) also plays an important role. To examine how strategy orderings contribute to persuasiveness, we first utilize a Variational Autoencoder model to disentangle content and rhetorical strategies in textual requests from a large-scale loan request corpus. We then visualize interplay between content and strategy through an attentional LSTM that predicts the success of textual requests. We find that specific (orderings of) strategies interact uniquely with a request’s content to impact success rate, and thus the persuasiveness of a request.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/featured/20-persuasion-strat.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/featured/20-persuasion-strat.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mapping Researchers with PeopleMap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/papers/people-map" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mapping Researchers with PeopleMap" /><published>2020-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/papers/people-map</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/papers/people-map">&lt;p&gt;Discovering research expertise at universities can be a difficult task.
Directories routinely become outdated, and few help in visually
summarizing researchers’ work or supporting the exploration of
shared interests among researchers. This results in lost opportunities
for both internal and external entities to discover new connections,
nurture research collaboration, and explore the diversity of research.
To address this problem, at Georgia Tech, we have been developing PeopleMap, an open-source interactive web-based tool that
uses natural language processing (NLP) to create visual maps for
researchers based on their research interests and publications. Requiring only the researchers’ Google Scholar profiles as input, PeopleMap generates and visualizes embeddings for the researchers,
significantly reducing the need for manual curation of publication information. To encourage and facilitate easy adoption and extension
of PeopleMap, we have open-sourced it under the permissive MIT. PeopleMap has received positive feedback and enthusiasm for expanding its adoption across Georgia Tech.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Saad-Falcon</name></author><summary type="html">Discovering research expertise at universities can be a difficult task. Directories routinely become outdated, and few help in visually summarizing researchers’ work or supporting the exploration of shared interests among researchers. This results in lost opportunities for both internal and external entities to discover new connections, nurture research collaboration, and explore the diversity of research. To address this problem, at Georgia Tech, we have been developing PeopleMap, an open-source interactive web-based tool that uses natural language processing (NLP) to create visual maps for researchers based on their research interests and publications. Requiring only the researchers’ Google Scholar profiles as input, PeopleMap generates and visualizes embeddings for the researchers, significantly reducing the need for manual curation of publication information. To encourage and facilitate easy adoption and extension of PeopleMap, we have open-sourced it under the permissive MIT. PeopleMap has received positive feedback and enthusiasm for expanding its adoption across Georgia Tech.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/papers/20-peoplemap.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/papers/20-peoplemap.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>